DAVID BERNHARD

WEB DEVELOPER

INFO

Location London

Phone 07969 343 253

Email davidbernhard@live.com

PRESENCE

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/

dave-bernhard

GitHub github.com/DaveCoded

Portfolio dave-bernhard.netlify.com

SKILLS

- Strong in HTML, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design and JavaScript
- React.js, GraphQL, Gatsby, jQuery, Bootstrap and Material UI
- Build Tooling: Gulp, Webpack, Babel and Git for version control
- WordPress custom themes
- · UI and UX design principles
- Proficient in Adobe programmes: Illustrator, Photoshop and XD
- Node.js, Express and MongoDB

EDUCATION

Master of Arts in English Literature
University of Edinburgh July 2013

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Made a custom theme for my friend's blog: www.gs-spot.co.uk
- Summited Margherita Peak, the highest in Uganda at 5,109m a.s.l.

SUMMARY

Junior Front-end Developer with 1 - 2 years' coding experience looking to work in a great team, learn from my peers and contribute to something more ambitious. Proven self-starter who founded his own company, changing from a career in private tutoring and book publishing.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Co-Founder, Eeny Meeny Creative

Aug 2018 - Present

- Developed the company website on WordPress just in time to land our first corporate client
- Implemented a professional design and development workflow using wireframes, mockups, Git version control and advanced build tools: Webpack, Babel and Gulp
- Attracted a client at a WordPres meetup and enabled her to monetise her established blog by adding a new feature that I proposed
- Fired our biggest client when a situation became untenable; a difficult decision that both rescued the business and taught me a great deal

Self-Employed Academic Tutor

Apr 2015 - Aug 2018

- Specialised in transforming timid children who were low on confidence into prepared, self-assured young people
- Enabled my very first pupil to go from expecting to fail in English, to attaining an academic scholarship to Dulwich College
- Sustained exceptional standards in myself and tutees, winning further clients purely through word of mouth and recommendation

Editorial Assistant

Apr 2014 - Apr 2015

- Commanded and executed the migration of all content to a new website, working with the web developer to master the CMS and maximise SEO
- Devised a 150 slide presentation for the external sales team
- Increased community engagement by 30% through the Twitter account